GIORGIO SAVRON

Full Stack Software Developer

850-225-6786 | giorgiosavron@me.com | Miami Beach, FL | www.giorgiosavron.com | linkedin.com/in/giorgio-savron | github.com/gsavr

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Software Developer with over 4 years' experience, specialized in React.js, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML/CSS, Tailwind CSS, Node.js, with an objective to develop websites and applications that are client-driven while ensuring that they are straightforward and engaging for the end user.

I intend to use my design, development and other skills while continuously advancing my skill set through additional programming and career development to remain at the forefront of an ever-changing technology landscape. In my free time, I am continuously learning new technologies and building projects, I also like to read fiction and travel.

SKILLS & CORE COMPETENCIES

- JavaScript
- React.js
- TypeScript
- HTML / CSS

- · Tailwind CSS
- Redux / Toolkit
- Node.js
- Git management
- MongoDB / SQL
- · React Native
- Docker / Containers
- Cloud Hosting
- Next.js / Gatsby.js
- Java / Python
- AWS / Heroku
- Data Engineering

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER, Self-employed

Software Development Technology Integration Cloud Applications Object-Oriented Programming

- Led implementation of code versioning via GitHub, and administered website hosting system via automatic deployment on Heroku, GoDaddy, decreasing deploy time by 35%.
- Built an MVC architecture and implemented with React.js, Express.js
- Developed and implemented fully-responsive templates using CSS, HTML, and tasks of persistence storage (CRUD).

SCIENCE TEACHER, Miami-Dade Co. Public Schools, Miami, FL

Oct 2012 - Dec 2021

Jan 2022 –Present

Education Leadership Behavioral Strategies Organization Development Time Management

- Prepared course materials following syllabi, created my own multimedia PowerPoints, Word
 Doc worksheets and homework assignments leading to increased student involvement and
 achievement of over 20% over initial testing.
- Evaluated class work, laboratory work, assignments using innovative technology including ZipGrade, and interactive quizzes on Microsoft Teams.

TECHNOLOGY DEVELOPER, Miami-Dade Democratic Executive Committee, Miami, FL

Jun – Dec 2020

Full-Stack Development Cloud Hosting

- Developed peer-to-peer SMS app based on Spoke from MoveOn.org allowing increased voter outreach by over 1.2 million texts over conversations, and lower cost per voter reached by 35%.
- Customized front end and services as needed by organization, integrated server and texting service and maintained accounts.

COMMUNICATIONS COORDINATOR, Edge Communications, Miami, FL

Seasonally 2012 - 2019

Data Analysis IT Management Acted as Campaign Field Organizer by specializing in using VoteBuilder - NGP VAN in order to prepare materials and volunteers for canvassing, phone calls to reach voters, allowing easier Data Entry and voter follow up increasing reach by 10% - 25% per campaign.

EDUCATION

University of Miami, Miami FL Full Stack Web Development Certification May 2019 Florida State University, Tallahassee FL Bachelor of Science in Biology May 2006